# Adam Lichnovský

Nationality: Address: Náměstí č.p. 3 Czech

Frýdlant nad Ostravicí Birthdate: 31.3.1983

73911 CellPhone: (+420) 728 051380

CzechRepublic Email: adam.lichnovsky@gmail.com

# Personal profile

IT Consultant, Excellent with Microsoft Server (R) products, also highly accomplished in field of Infrastructure Design (including several domains, namely: network, storage, servers, security) and Enterprise Architecture. Very good understanding of customer business domain. Anticipates customer needs and discovers alternative solutions. Proactively markets companies towards customers and identifies potential sales cases. Guides the customer in business and solution decisions (counseling, advising, and coaching). Dealing frequently with the more complex and demanding issues in the area of expertise. Planning of own and others work.

Evaluates and investigates technical platform products, hardware and integration between them within different service areas. Guides and influences others within own area. Analyses and improves current ways of working. Considered to be competence lead within the unit and by customer(s). Customer focus Very good understanding of customer business domain. Anticipates customer needs and discovers alternative solutions. Is able to explain and present highly complex solutions.

Meticulous, highly skilled active cooperative team member with sense for responsibility. Accomplished in developing and sustaining enterprise infrastructure (network, servers, data storage and relating devices). Deep knowledge of Microsoft Windows Servers OS and related technologies (MS SQL Server, MS SharePoint Server, and MS Exchange with MS Lync Server), as well about VMware provided virtualization platform (vCenter, ESX, ESXi, vCloud), and storage systems from NetApp, HP and EMC.

Highly aware of enterprise needs todays expressed as enterprise architecture which helps to optimize across the enterprise the often fragmented legacy of processes (both manual and automated) into an integrated environment that is responsive to change and supportive of the delivery of the business strategy. Very often is a part of company enterprise architecture the framework TOGAFv9.1 (The Open Group Architecture Framework) with integrated framework for support and delivery services called Information Technology Infrastructure Library (ITIL) methodology to define incidents, problems, and changes.

# Career history

February 2015 - Now

Company: Verizon Enterprise Solutions (contractor OKIN Group a.s./division BPS)

Position: Assigned Client Engineer

Responsibility: Support and delivery for customer server domain, storage domain, virtualization domain and network domain.

Work content:

Assigned Client Engineer (hereinafter ACE) is responsible for providing and sustaining contracted managed services to assigned external clients. Determines client organization's software, hardware and/or network system requirements, and delivers advice on how to acquire technology solutions that are aligned with the client's business strategy and processes. ACE provides delivery of service for complex solutions that require specialized knowledge. ACE acts proactively towards success of technical services and administrative support to assigned

clients, while simultaneously providing an escalation point for complex technical issues associated with client specific, customized solutions to the operations team. ACE audits, reports and performs quality assurance over client infrastructure and information systems operations (Ops) and architectures (Arch). Performing and completes information technology systems consultancy from areas of technology strategy and transformation, information systems (IS) security, data strategy, systems architecture, custom systems development, new installations and migrations of function/business area applications, and networking. Evaluates and investigates technical platform products, hardware and integration between them within different service areas. The ACE performs a balanced role of administrative functions as well as reactive escalation support for investigating and resolving incidents and problems.

## Capabilities & skills:

ACE works in enterprise environment supported by various frameworks, architectures, technologies and models. From the frameworks should be mentioned the most important ITILv3, TOGAF 9.1 and PRINCE. Area of expertise at technologies for ACE contains Server domain, Storage domain, Network domain and Virtualization domain. Each domain contains set of technologies to deliver services, which are set up for covering client requirements. Server domain is set of hardware and software layers. Hardware mainly delivered by vendors like Cisco UCS, HP, and Dell. As software we count operating systems (Microsoft Windows Server 2003 and higher), web server software (Microsoft IIS, or SharePoint Server), authentication services (Active Directory), and database software (Microsoft SQL Server). Storage domain is containing platforms such as HP 3Par, EMC VNX Series, NetApp FAS and backup solution Simpana CommVault. Network domain in Verizon is very complex solution running on wide scale of vendors delivering their products to support Verizon networking technologies. And Virtualization domain is based on Cisco UCS and VMware products.

#### Scope/Complexity:

ACE gains knowledge and experience of assigned clients in order to be the resident expert within Verizon on the client environmental architecture and maintain accurate and detailed documentation required for the successful support of the client environment. ACE activities are supported by a 24x7 operations team, who support many clients and focus on real-time monitoring, incident response, change execution, with compute and network infrastructure expertise. Dealing frequently with the more complex and demanding issues in the area of expertise. ACE is leading technical teams during crisis, while services are under the repair. Planning of own and others work.

October 2010 - August 2014

Company: **Tieto Czech s.r.o.**Position: Senior Service Architect

Responsibility: Server domain: VMware ESX, Citrix XenApp, Microsoft Hyper-V, and Data Security

## Work content:

Responsible for providing information technology (IT) systems strategy, development and/or integration services to external clients. Responsible for maintaining and developing certain service or service family within his/her own service area. Service Architect has knowledge of the techniques used to provide the services to external customers. Determines client organization's software, hardware and/or network system requirements, and delivers advice on how to acquire technology solutions that are aligned with the client's business strategy and processes. Successfully completes technology/systems consulting projects such as Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP), technology strategy and transformation, information systems (IS) security, data strategy, systems architecture, custom systems development, new installations and migrations of function/business area applications, enterprise application integration (EAI) Web, IP and online solutions, and networking. Evaluates and investigates technical platform products, hardware and integration between them within different service areas. Service Architect audits infrastructure architectures along with other internal architects. Organizes and leads the work of enterprise level technical architecture team in international projects. Service Architect provides pre-sales support.

### Capabilities & skills:

Guides and influences others within own area. Analyses and improves current ways of working. Considered to be competence lead within the unit and by customer(s). Customer focus Very good understanding of customer business domain. Anticipates customer needs and discovers alternative solutions. Is able to explain and present highly complex solutions.

Adam Lichnovský: Curriculum Vitae

Scope/Complexity:

Dealing frequently with the more complex and demanding issues in the area of expertise. Planning of own and others work. May act as team leader.

December 12, 2015

July 2009 - September 2010

Company: IBM Global Services Delivery Center Czech Republic, s.r.o.

Position: IT Specialist 2nd and 3rd level support Responsibility: Windows Servers, VMware ESX

Work content:

Work on WINTEL (**WIN**dows In**TEL**) server installation and configuration based on received specification. Customization of server settings on demand. Troubleshooting/investigations in WINTEL server area.

Capabilities & skills:

Second and third level support Windows System Administrator covers standard administration of MS Windows based operating systems as Windows Server 2003/2008 or higher, connected services, infrastructure and Middleware related to distributed server systems. Understand the interactions and dependencies among components of server infrastructure and provides solutions for complex problems.

Scope/Complexity:

Dealing frequently with daily issues in the area of expertise. Work on daily basis and partly planning of own work.

June 2008 - June 2009

Company: MOBIS Automotive Czech s.r.o.

One of the most important Korea based module and car components producer and exclusive supplier for Hyundai Motor Manufacturing Czech.

Position: IT Specialist 2nd and 3rd level support

Responsibility: Windows Servers and Network administrator (Cisco)

Work content:

Work on network and server domain, performing installation and configuration based on received specification. Through custom engineering execute customization of server settings on demand. Troubleshooting and investigations in Microsoft Windows Server area, and Cisco Networking area (Catalysts, ASAs, IPS).

Capabilities & skills:

Windows System Administrator covers standard administration of MS Windows based operating systems as Windows Server 2003 and 2008, connected services, infrastructure. Understand the interactions and dependencies among components of server infrastructure and provides support for complex problems.

Scope/Complexity:

Dealing frequently with daily issues in the area of expertise. Work on daily basis and partly planning of own work. Administration of company network (Cisco products), administration of servers running on Windows Server services like Active Directory, DHCP, DNS, WSUS, and WebSense.

September 2007 - December 2007

Company: GE Money Multiservis, a.s.

Position: Technical Specialist

Responsibility: supporting user connected to company network trough terminals from trade centers

Adam Lichnovský: Curriculum Vitae

# Education

High School Frýdlant and Ostravicí - focused on mathematic and information technology 1998 - 2002

Unfinished - Institute of Chemical Technology in Prague 2002 - 2008

# Languages

Czech Proficient / native speaker English Proficient / fluent speaker

German Pre-intermediate

## **Courses Seminars**

TOGAF 9.1 Foundation, ITILv3, SCRUM, LEAN, Six Sigma, Verizon Lean Six Sigma

BMC Remedy ARS, BMC Atrium Discovery and Dependency Mapping, BMC Server Automation, BMC Blade Logic Server Automation, BMC Patrol

IBM Tivoli infrastructure, IBM ITCS300 version 11.0 Education, IBM Access Management Framework Education

Microsoft Windows Server Installation and Administration, Microsoft PowerShell Scripting, Microsoft Active Directory – advanced

VMware Infrastructure 3: Install and Configure (VMware ESX Server 3.5 and Virtual Center 2.5)

Installing and Configuring Citrix XenApp 5.0 for Windows Server 2008, Advanced Administration for Citrix XenApp 5.0 for Windows Server 2008

Hitachi Data Systems Foundations THI2264 / THE2264

**EMC VNX Solution Training** 

# Knowledge and skills

Architect / Administrator

Professional

Microsoft Windows Server 2000, 2003, 2008, 2012, 2016

MS Windows Server roles:

- Active Directory
- DNS
- IIS
- Failover Clustering
- File Server
- NPS
- DHCP
- Hyper-V

Microsoft SQL Server

Microsoft Exchange Server

Microsoft Lync Server

Microsoft SharePoint Server with Application Fabric

Microsoft System Center

VMware ESX, ESXi, vSphere, vCenter, vCloud

Symantec System Center

Cyber-Ark Privileged Identity Management Suite

Citrix XenApp (formerly Presentation Server)

#### Intermediate

IBM Director, IBM Tivoli Storage Manager

Cisco Catalyst, Cisco ASA, Cisco Aironet, Cisco MARS

Linux, NetApp FAS Storage, HITACHI NAS Storage, EMC VNX Series

Solarwinds Network Performance Monitor

**NetIQ** Monitoring

Simpana CommVault

#### Basic

UNIX (AIX), Cygwin, Lotus Domino

#### Programmer

Professional

PowerShell, C# .NET, LUA, Visual Basic Script (VBS)

Basic

Java, Visual Basic For Application, C/C++ (various standard), Assembler

Security Frameworks and Standards

PCI DSSv3, CIS, SANS, ISO/IEC 27001:2013, SOX

### User

Microsoft Office, Microsoft Visio, Microsoft Visual Studio, Matlab, AutoCAD, Lotus Notes, Lotus Administrator, LATEX, SAP, BMC Remedy, HP Service Center, NetBeans

## Interest

Skiing, reading books, football, puzzle solving, mountain climbing, information technology.